Guide to the Jean-Paul Sartre Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Jean-Paul Sartre collection
1950-1970
GEN MSS 143
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.4
(1 box)
The collection consists of writings by Sartre.
Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1905-1980
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This listing encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts by or pertaining to Jean-Paul Sartre acquired by gift or purchase from various sources by the Beinecke Library. Materials acquired prior to April 1995 have been organized as Series I, Writings, arranged alphabetically by title. Materials acquired after April 1995 are located in Series II, Additions since April 1995, and are listed in accession order.
Authors, French -- 20th Century -- Archives; Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1905-1980
- Writings, Series I
  - [Tintoretto]
    - Autograph manuscript corrected, incomplete, relating to Tintoretto, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      1 item (55 leaves); 27 cm. Pages numbered 1-55; numbers not in Sartre's hand. Purchased in 1987.
    - Autograph manuscript corrected, incomplete, relating to Tintoretto, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      1 item (41 leaves); 27 cm. Pages numbered 1-41; numbers not in Sartre's hand. Purchased in 1990.
  - "Nekrassov," holograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, [ca. 1955] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    1 item (55 leaves); 27 cm.
    45 manuscript pages and 10 typescript
    pages.
    Contains drafts of several tableaux
    from this play, including Tableau II
    and Tableau VI.
    Includes a small diagram of the set
    for one tableau.
    Purchased in 1995.
  - "Le Sursis," holograph manuscript, corrected., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4-19)
    810 pages.
    Autograph presentation inscription
    to Hervé Favre, dated 13 Oct 1945,
    on first leaf.
- Additions since April 1995, n.d.; Series II
  - "Sequestres d'Altona," holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    1 item (40 leaves); 27 cm.
    Pages numbered 1-40; numbers not
    in Sartre's hand.
    Purchased in 1996.
  - "Ainsi la penseé revolutionnaire est une penseé en situation....," holograph manuscript, annotated, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    1 item (7 L.); 31 cm.
    Purchased in 1999.
    Acc: 990817-m
  - "Nekrassov," holograph manuscript, [1955 Jun] (Box 2, Folder 22)
    1 item (24 L.); 27 cm. x 21 cm.
    Version of a scene corresponding
    to Scene IV in the finished
    version.
    Acc: 19991027-e
  - [Huis clos], holograph manuscript, [1944] (Box 2, Folder 23)
    1 item (1 L.); 21 cm.
    Synopsis submitted by Sartre
    to L'Arbalète in 1994.
    Purchased in 2001.
    Acc: 20011218-c
  - [Huis clos], page proof, corrected, [1944] (Box 2, Folder 24)
    1 item (8 L.); 25 cm.
    Page proofs, heavily corrected and
    with additions, numbered 7, 52-57,
    66.
    Acc: 20011218-b
  - "Après Budapest, Sartre parle," manuscript notes, typescript, and printed version, 1956 Nov 9 (Box 2, Folder 25-28)
    3 items.
    Purchased in 2002.
    Acc: 20021028-p
  - "Communistes et la Paix," manuscript, revised, [1954 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    1 item.
    Purchased in 2003.
    Acc: 20030804-c
  - [Notes on theater], manuscript, [1960] (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Acc.: 20030911-ak